Just first I want to thank all the
scouts. Uh Chad, Ed, Katie, John, Dean,
Coach Harbaugh, all the coaches, our
doctors, training staff, everybody,
equipment, everyone has a hand in the
draft and uh a lot of work goes into it,
our whole personnel staff, weeds,
everybody. There's so many people that
the draft are included in the draft that
don't get recognition. and uh and it's
just it can't happen without them. You
think about going to the combine, the
rooms, all the all the organization that
we do. Uh
all the hard hours put in. It's it's fun
to sit up there for three days and make
the picks, but you got to reflect on
what what's what's gone into it. And uh
just really proud of everyone's efforts
and appreciate John and Dean and AG for
giving us this opportunity to do this
every year. So, um, but in terms of
today, it was a lot of fun and, uh,
uh, you know, I just it's fun to get
picks and it's fun to use them. So,
leave let these guys say something.
>> Yeah,
>> I'm not here to talk. I was just here to
be a part of this day. It was an epic
day. Uh, and like you said, Joe, I mean,
that was uh you deserve a ton of credit
and so does everybody involved, but uh
that was uh
that was uh heck of a day for the
Chargers.
Yeah, I feel the same. Obviously, just
thankful for everybody involved. Uh Joe
and Jim did a great job leading and uh
just we really really improved the team
this weekend. So, couldn't be happier.
Can we uh roll through these things here
and Sure. Get some thoughts starting
with uh Brandon
>> fast.
>> Fast.
>> No. Um well, first like one thing I I'll
say is you know we start the day and uh
you guys know last night I told you we
go up and we're we're going to stack the
board. We kind of spread them out
identify who the targets are. We had a
row the top row were seven names. We got
four of them with our first four picks
which is an awesome feeling. Um so um he
was number one and frankly our trade
back I don't even know what pick that
was 86 right he would have been in the
mix at 86. So to go back pick up two
more picks and get the guy that we could
have easily taken there uh is really
exciting. So, but just a dynamic,
explosive playmaker. Uh, Mike loved, the
scouts loved you. Just the speed jumps
out on film. His ability to track the
ball downfield is is really elite and,
uh, ability to take the ball on the run
and gone. So, really explosive playmaker
that we think just really adds and opens
up this offense. Do
>> you see him doing some return at all?
>> Yeah, we'll definitely throw him back
there. and he hasn't he's I think he had
one return this year for good we talked
about great yards 43 yards so
>> give him another shot you know
>> just body typewise does he remind you of
anybody that you've seen at you know
that that size 164
>> um I mean he's a little higher than 164
now I think but um
>> yeah you know there's been a number of
guys that have come through uh we kind
of run through the list of players
there's not a a lot, right? They're
they're kind of outliers, guys like him.
>> Yeah, Deshawn. He's been compared to
Deshawn.
>> Tyreek's thicker than him, uh, coming
out, but that similar size, height,
speed combination, but Tyreek was a
thicker guy. DJ was definitely a leaner.
>> Right.
>> Yeah, Tyreek was thicker.
It reminded Mike McDaniel of somebody
and I hate to compare because whenever
he compares, right, somebody gets
diminished, but uh you can ask you can
ask Mike who um he compared to.
>> We mentioned his name here.
>> You did. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah, I think so. I think I think
you mentioned
>> I think you mentioned both names.
>> Something he coached.
>> Uh just moving down the list here. Uh
Travis Burke, tackle out of out of
Memphis. Chad, you want to start?
>> I mean, just a massive human being, you
know, huge, outstanding length. Uh this
guy, you know, he's really he's tough,
you know, really tough competitor. Uh
what stands out to me is just the
effort, the finishing ability,
nastiness, you know what I mean, in
terms of finishing players. So, I mean,
he's uh he he and he's he still got a
ton of upside, you know what I mean?
he's going to get better and and that
that's uh that's just someone we felt
really comfortable with at that point
and uh just going to reinforce our
offensive line. So, we were really
excited to get him where we got him.
>> Kind of flex tackle, you know,
>> swing tackle. Yeah, swing tackle type
guy. Um you know, coach I think said it
and he said he's not going to talk, but
he should talk. Um, but uh, you know,
this where he came from, you know, where
he's been, he just there's so much more
room for growth. Chad mentions that, you
know, just get him in a in a pro
organization and let him just really
flourish, you know, but talented guy.
Chad mentioned the physicality. It's
fun. I think I saw some of the
highlights when after we picked him
where he's just bulldozing guys in the
open field and but just a lot of a lot
of talent, a lot of upside still to go.
Yeah, I love the hustle.
>> Not afraid to finish. Chad said it, but
uh I mean he not afraid to finish down
the field.
>> Uh you know, out past the hashes. Uh and
this a lot of lot of good this you know,
you get you get a
sometimes you get a favorite player and
this is just definitely one of mine in
this draft.
>> The Jens Smith
>> feels like a deep field.
>> Yep.
>> Center field.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Definitely. Uh rangy safety.
Um you know, instincts, sees it quick,
reads the quarterback well, and then uh
aggressive downhill. Uh long, athletic,
they kind of play him all over. I mean,
he's more backhand stuff, but you see
him down as the rover and physical fill
in the alley and uh not afraid to
tackle.
>> You have a follow-up question? I know
what it is. Go ahead, ask it. I'll tell
you what I saw.
>> He'll get in the mix. He's going to get
down there. To me, it looked like a,
>> you know, some technique stuff
happening.
>> Exactly. Yeah. And then so like,
>> you know, tackle tackling can be
improved if the one two is there. And
the one two is definitely there. And so
you look at him, he comes up, he gets a
he has a good number of tackles on film.
You know, all safeties miss tackles. We
talk about this in draft meetings.
There's there were safeties ahead of him
that missed tackles, but they're still
good football players. You just clean up
the technique, clean up the angles, the
leverage. If they don't have the
willingness, then you got a problem.
He's got the willingness.
>> Angles wise, how much of that is is
coaching, do you guys think? Like how
much can you improve a guy's angles? How
much of just instincts?
>> It's it depends on the play. Sometimes
it's over aggression. You you you
beline into the angle. It's just about
tempoing the football tempoing the
football, matching the pace of the ball
carrier, uh, reading the keys. Those
those things can be taught
and we got great safety coaches and and
Adam and Chris. So, I'm not I'm not
worried about that at all.
>> I listen, here's what I'll say. Yeah, I
know what your questions would be. I've
been around some really good safeties in
my career that weren't really good
tacklers their first year in the league,
and they they've done pretty good. So
tackling improves with safeties
>> and he's a get I mean he gets him on the
ground but he's more of a nickel. He's
more of a he's more of a
uh another safety just another one in
the five and we're we're a nickel that
can get Derwin who's really good at
tackling
>> closer to line of scrimmage. Uh so
that's kind of the way I see see this is
a great that's a great pick.
>> Great pick. Mhm.
>> Versatile like coach and Joe talked
about, you know, he's really explosive.
He's a 42 and a half vertical guy. Can
help us on special teams. He's going to
help us in a lot of ways.
>> Uh
Nick Barry,
what did you guys see from him?
>> Uh another physical player, very
technically sound. Uh plays the game the
way we we play it. you know, square,
uses his hands well, he's got good
instincts, block recognition, locate the
ball, effort to it. Um, just just a guy
that we honestly feel like he's the type
of player that can get better and
develop into a starter. All these guys,
everyone feel like they have start we
have starter grades on all these guys
from at least one scout or one coach.
Um, but he's a guy that just, you know,
he's he played behind some guys last
year in the rotation and then this year
had a chance to really get more a
greater role and uh he just you see it
like he's just a physical, smart,
instinctive, tough guy, big man, knows
how to use his hands and uh makes plays
at the point in pursuit and uh and great
kid and he's he's one of our blueest
star players. So um uh so a lot to like
with him.
>> He told us that he was
around 340
two years ago. Got down because he was
playing like 318 to 322. Felt like he
needed to get in better shape to be able
to play a higher percentage of snaps.
How attractive is that in the scouting
process when you see a guy in college
who
>> kind of makes that transformation and
then you see it, you know, goes from
like 17% snaps and 24 to 42.
>> Yeah. I mean, it's really it is
impressive, you know, and and just shows
that he put the work in, you know, and
this is a guy that plays with a lot of
effort, a lot of strain. He has, like
Joe talked about, he plays with
violence, you know, he's got contact
balance. He's hard to really hard to
move and, you know, despite losing the
weight, he still plays really sturdy in
there, plays a really good like contact
balance. Uh, can stack and shed. So,
really excited about him. I mean, he's
he's a he's got charger mentality is
what we call it. He really does. and uh
so excited to get him.
>> What jumped out to you guys about how he
looked against Bantis in that that S&'s
he's just he's consistent like he just
really is. He he just again we said it
hands hat extend tear off go get to the
ball, you know, and it's just the way we
teach it and and he can execute it.
last two year.
>> Yeah.
>> Guard, guard,
>> guard, guard. Um, but again, guard, you
know, Logan has played both tackle and
guard. Both big frame guys, athleticism,
physical. You watch them both, they're
physical. Uh there's some plays, you
know, just that pop in my head about,
you know, like with Alex, they just some
kind of wow athletic plays when you're
watching them out in space. Uh, and then
Logan, just think about the finishing.
Um and but you know he started his
career at Virginia and then you know
worked at tackle and then down to guard
and uh a lot of starts in his career and
uh just really like the way that the
mentality they both play the game with.
They're both physical players uh come
off the ball and uh look to finish
blocks and
sturdy big men.
>> So most linemen you guys have drafted
since 1991 I think. How did it turn out
that way you think?
>> Um, like I told you yesterday, there's a
one of you guys asked a question about
linemen and I said there's a lot of
linemen we like in this draft still and
like I say, we take the best player
available and uh it breeds competition
and uh we just they were there and they
were they were the highest guys and uh
you know we didn't force you know we
could have
I mean, if anything, you take three
linemen and we took another one, you
know, and it's just because he's the
highest guy, you know, and uh let's take
the best players, make the team as
competitive and as good as we can make
it, you know. So,
>> uh did you get a corner? Um just the way
the board fell.
>> Way the board fell. Yeah. Like I mean
you got there were there was a point
on in the fourth round where I'm looking
like okay it might be a corner with one
of these fourth round picks and then and
then maybe a corner with the fifth and
then it just just it just cleared out.
So just when we were up corners just
weren't high enough when before the run
came and then they kind of evaporated
>> before 145. Uh, no. I'd say definitely
before 202. I mean, now a lot of players
evaporated in those
>> near
140 145.
>> Yeah, 145. But when but when we were up
on those picks, the corners just weren't
the highest players on the board.
>> Do you feel like you want to potentially
add there or you feel good about, you
know, Dante, Tardee, Cam, you talked
about Nico and Eric, too.
>> Yeah. and and ice, you know, like we
feel good about the room.
>> Won't say we'll never we won't add like
I tell tell you guys like
>> roster is not set until we set it at 53,
you know, uh free agency extends all the
way through the season. So, um I'm
definitely always open whenever we can
make the team better, we'll we'll do it.
So, I wouldn't say we're we're uh done
there, but I wouldn't say we're shopping
aggressively either.
any chance to get a seven?
>> Uh
there was one bad trade offer and so
just like no, you know, um let's let's
we would have had to move off of one of
our sixes and you go back too far and it
just it wasn't it wasn't worth it. We we
had players we liked so let's just take
the players we liked.
>> Jim, I know you said you were talking
but just how excited are you for like
what you guys have in the O line room
now? you know, bringing in four new guys
and just the competition that you're
going to have there through the spring
and summer.
>> Um, very excited. the season ended. I
think we had three linemen under
contract, you know, now to have um
>> 14
>> 14 under contract is uh and and young,
you know, uh three four years of uh of
contract and development uh is uh it
fires me up.
>> You made a decision on Quinn's fifth
year. We're still talking through it. We
have till
>> May.
>> May 1st.
>> Yep.
>> I'll let you know when we do.
>> I don't think you're
waiting for the announcement.
>> Going to set the seven
>> to start the day that you got across the
top and you get four of them. Is that
>> you projecting where they're going to
be? cuz with all those picks moving up
and down, was it kind of a weird draft
where you didn't feel like you really
had to move as much to get your guys?
>> Yeah. Uh so the way we do it, not to
give away trade secrets, we just say,
"Hey, who are our top guys, you know,
and uh it's it's already set or we we
set the the whole draft process. It's
not like we just start pulling, you
know, it's already set. It was like,
okay, these are the guys that we really
feel can impact us still." and there
were seven of them left and uh and so it
was just like you know bam bam you know
and uh you know we we felt like the only
one we moved up for was Travis and uh
again swing tackle and we used one of
those sixes to move up a little bit just
to just to secure him because we all
know what we went through last year with
tackles so uh it's a guy that we feel
has starter tools and you know but uh
definitely felt like it was a draft
where
there were going to be players taken
where you're like, "Wow, man. We didn't
we didn't like that guy as much." It
just it was a more open draft, but it
was a deeper draft, too. It really was
like in terms of once you got, you know,
past the first round into the second,
third round. So, I really felt like the
third and fourth round was going to be
productive for us.
the uh social team tweeted out a shot of
Mike McDaniel saying he was going to
take his shirt off if you drafted
Brendon Thompson. Are you going to hold
him? It didn't look like it, but he did.
Did you ask him not to do that? Like
what is he paying that off later? What
are we doing?
>> I don't know if we'll do that, you know.
Um
maybe maybe, you know, we'll see. We'll
see. When a coach says something like
that to you before the player is
drafted, I mean, it's sort of an odd
thing to say like, but it does certainly
show how much he's invested in trying to
get to that player. What does that kind
of do to the room to set the tone for
the day?
>> It's conviction.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. He's
>> We appreciate conviction.
>> Yeah.
>> He's Mike Mike does a great job
communicating the players he likes and
the the vision he has for them. And you
know, terms for Chad and I, I don't want
to speak for Chad, but like it helps us
really set the board and uh and create a
plan, you know. So, I appreciate it and
I appreciate him leaving his shirt on.
>> Just overall the communication was
>> awesome.
>> Yeah.
>> A++.
>> Yeah. With everyone. With everyone.
>> Everybody.
>> Not just And not just this weekend. the
the whole process leading up to to this
draft
>> with uh Nick. Do you feel like only
having one year as a starter and one
year of real production impacted his
where he went at all?
>> Yeah, can I guess you know you could say
that you know I I don't know what other
we're not in other draft rooms. So I
know what we do is we evaluate the
player the year before. I can think of a
lot of players over my career where I
when I was a scout, I'd look at a player
in the spring and say, "Hey, this yeah,
this guy' be be good, you know, be a
good backup, you know, because he's
playing limited reps or you see
something like, hey, this guy's got
potential if he just plays more, you
know, so you give him that low end, that
catch grade where I think he could be a
starter, but I'm unsure because he's
only played and uh and then they play
and uh and you see And so I I don't know
how other teams think. I just know when
we did the evals on them, our scouts
that went in there saw a guy that they
felt they could be a starter and uh and
I
we we believe in them, you know, and our
coaches saw it that way. So um but yeah,
it's
getting the experience. Maybe it's where
he started, you know, the where he was
at the beginning of the year. you know,
he may not have been as perceived as
high, but I know when we took him, there
was people that, you know, it's a great
thing when you get those texts, you
know, like, ah, man, would have taken
them, you know, if we had that pick or
if we're if we were next, you know, so
we do the same thing, you know, and you
don't you don't send those after every
pick, you know, you send them to your
buddies that it's true to, you know,
it's true about. Yeah, it's great too
when the
highest player on the board at that
point is also a position of need. I we
had four defensive tackles.
>> Yeah. Now we got five.
>> And at right at that point, Nick was the
highest rated player and it was it was
the most need and that you just feel
like the football gods are being very
very good to you.
>> They're the picks you get most excited
about. like it truthfully like like oh
man he he fills a need and you're and
with him we had what 14 picks to wait
since we took Genesis and it was
is he going to get there? Is he going to
get there? because he was the highest
guy. And you're just you're hoping no
one else takes him. And uh and when they
get there, you're fired up.